本字幕僅供學習交流 嚴禁用于商業用途
長城名列人類文明的壯舉之一
THE GREAT WALL HAS STOOD FOR CENTURIES
千年來 屹立不倒
AS ONE OF MANKIND'S MOST ENDURING WONDERS.
它綿延五千五百英里
IT SPANS OVER 5500 MILES
歷經一千七百多年修建完成
AND TOOK MORE THAN 1700 YEARS TO BUILD.
它防御著形形色色的敵人 有真實的故事 也有傳說
IT PROTECTED FROM MANY DANGERS. SOME ARE KNOWN. SOME ARE LEGEND.
這就是其中的一則傳說
THIS IS ONE OF THE LEGENDS.
長   城
THE GREAT WALL
納吉 把馬放開！
Najid, cut the horses loose!
我們得調頭回去
We have to turn back.
都走了六個月了
We have been riding for six months.
- 我們死了20幾個人了 - 還沒死光呢
- And we've lost twenty men. - But we survived.
對 快死光了
Yes. By chance.
下一個死的 就該輪到我們了
Any one of us could have met that same fate.
我們幾個是最棒的 記住我們來的目地
We were the strongest. Remember why you're here.
要照以前 你敢這么說  我早把你給殺死了
In the West, we would be enemies, and I wouldd have to kill you.
好在我們的目標一致
At least here we have a common goal.
對 黑火藥
Oh, yes. This black powder.
它能把空氣變成火焰 一次就能干掉十幾個人…
It turns air into fire. And kills a dozen men at one time.
- 這是我夢寐以求的武器 - 那要只是一個傳說呢？
- It is a weapon of our dreams. - What if it's just a myth?
有人發誓說 千真萬確
Men have sent word that it's real.
那些人 都死了
And those men are dead.
現在該輪到我們了
And we are next.
沒有地圖
We have no maps,
沒有藥品
no medicines,
沒有吃的
and no food.
不行 誰都不能回去
No one is going back.
我們先清點一下剩下的東西
We take inventory of what we have left
干完這一票再說
and finish what we started.
沒什么可用的
There's not much here.
月色很好 等馬吃飽了 我們就走
The moon is strong. When the horse are fresh, we move.
- 去哪里？ - 往北
- To where? - North.
契丹人如果追上來  就在山里干掉他們
If they keep after us, we'll kill them in the mountains.
一塊磁石
The magnet.
太重了
Too heavy.
- 沒什么用 - 留著
- Useless. - I'll have it.
你自己拿著
It's all yours.
伙計 你要背塊石頭過沙漠啊？
Amigo, only you would carry a stupid magnet through the desert.
我能用它做個指南針
I can use it to make a compass.
里澤蒂不行了
Rizzeti won't make it.
他傷得太重
The wound is festering.
- 我們現在等于是拖著一具尸體在走 - 我聽見了！
- We'll be dragging a corpse. - I heard that.
死在那里 是他的選擇
He's earned the right to die where he wants.
我也被人扔下過兩次
I've been left for dead twice.
- 都倒霉了 - 誰倒霉了？
- It was bad luck. - For who?
那些扔下我的人
The people who left me.
他們去哪里了？
Where are they?
是契丹人？
Hill tribes?
不是人類
It's no man.
那是什么？
Then what is it?
不管是什么…
Whatever it is...
牠在捕食
it's hunting.
- 什么東西？ - 不知道
- What was that? - I don't know.
我砍了牠的爪子
I took its hand.
那…那我們現在…
We need to move.
趕快走
Agreed.
得帶著這個
I'll take the hands with us.
帶牠干嘛？
What the hell for?
得弄清楚 牠是什么東西
So someone can tell me what I just killed.
這幫王八蛋  還真是鍥而不舍啊？
Persistent bastards, aren't they?
我們上山去 居高臨下打
We'll take the rise, make a stand there.
人要死了 還得兜個風
What a long shitting way to go to die.
這下完了
Mother of God.
放箭！
Fire!
這樣回去 也是死
I have no need to go down fighting.
沒錯
Agreed.
和前面的紳士們 碰碰運氣吧
I say we take our chanches with the gents in front of us.
我可很久沒有投降過了
I haven't surrendered in a while, eh.
那就再來一次
It'll come back to you.
只要你聽我的 平安無事
Follow my lead. We'll be fine.
當然得聽你的
Of course, my friend.
我們是朋友嘛
Where you go, I follow.
都這樣了 還能平安無事？
You're doing such a great job already.
傳鹿軍 鄭將軍！
All commanders to the great hall!
傳鶴軍 林將軍！
All commanders report to the General!
閃開！
Make way!
急傳鶴軍 林將軍！
All commanders to the large hall!
閃開！
Make way!
傳鹿軍 鄭將軍！
Commander Lin is needed immediately!
急傳鶴軍 林將軍！
Calling Commander Lin!
紹殿帥 急傳林將軍！
Commander Lin is needed immediately!
他們對那個感興趣
They know what it is.
而且表情十分凝重
And they don't look so happy to see it.
必須得找個機會殺出去
All the more reason to get the hell out of here.
我們的兵器在桌上
Our weapons are on that table.
你確定 你沒瘋？
Have you lost your mind?
我只要拿到弓箭 就能干掉那些士兵
I can take the guards on the perimeter with my bow.
你去干掉那幾個當官的
You cut the legs out from under the officers.
你真具有非凡的想象力
I must confess this is not my favorite plan.
哪里撿的？
Where was this found?
是問我嗎？
You speak English.
審完了就殺
Fantastic.
我問你在哪里撿的？
Where was this found?
不是撿的
It wasn't found.
是我砍的
It was taken.
之前 牠殺了我們三個人
That thing killed three men before we took it down.
在哪里？
Where?
騎馬往北 兩天
Two days ride.
山里
North, in the mountains.
他說在北山 距此兩日行程
He says two days ride north, in the mountains.
- 他自稱 曾斬殺一頭饕餮 - 兩日？
- They claim to have killed it. - Two days?
比我們預計的時間提前了
Earlier than we expected.
王軍師！
Strategist Wang!
殿帥 我在聽
I'm listening, General.
是他們殺的？
The two of them killed it?
- 你們兩個 一起殺的？ - 那個…我們…
- Two of you, you did this? - Well...
- 我殺的 - 你一個人？
- I killed it. - Alone?
- 他說 是他一個人殺的 - 他一個人？
- He claims to have killed it alone. - By himself?
怎么可能？
Impossible.
你是怎么殺的？
Tell me how.
就那么一砍一劈
A swing of the sword.
牠爪子斷了
The hand came away clean.
身體向后一倒 掉進山谷里了
The beast fell back into a chasm.
- 你們來這里干什么？ - 我們是商人
- Why are you here? - We came to trade.
遇上了埋伏
We were ambushed.
來人！
Guards!
你們是軍人
You are soldiers.
林將軍
Commander Lin.
不可
Wait.
殿帥
General.
他們謊稱 是遭遇契丹人伏擊的商人
They claim to be traders who were ambushed.
這蠻夷 真能吹牛
These barbarians are liars.
未必
Perhaps not.
有饕餮斷掌為證
They brought the claw here.
刀劍切口 一目了然
The wound is fresh.
在他們的劍和衣服上 都有綠血
There is green blood on his sword.
完全有那個可能
Those prove his story.
末將以為 無論巧合與否  應立即處死二人
To protect our secret, we must kill them.
- 以防后患 - 林將軍說的是
- Eliminate the possibility of trouble. - I agree.
砍了算了！
We should kill them!
殿帥
General.
他們來歷 尚未查明
Until we find the truth,
- 我看 還是多留幾天吧 - 報！
- I advise we keep them alive. - Alert!
啟稟殿帥大人 烽火臺 狼煙四起！
General, signals from the smoke towers!
有敵來犯！
We are under attack!
先將俘虜 押至北樓
Take them to the stockade.
- 傳令 全體將士 準備迎敵！ - 是！準備迎敵！
- All stations on full alert! - Yes! All stations on full alert!
小娘子 妳真要處決我們嗎？
Are you killing us, Sister?
我們兩只可憐的迷途羔羊？
Two lost travelers?
這到底怎么回事啊？
What's happening here?
你不是保證平安無事的嗎？
Is this bitch going to kill us?
先別這么緊張
I think she'd like that.
真要殺我們啊 親愛的
If it is death, my dear,
你下得了手嗎
we need time to pray.
我得跟她套套交情
I'm trying here.
小娘子 我知道 你們被圍攻了
Sister, I know a siege when I see one.
可是你們城墻這么高 不用耽心的
What comes at you so hard you need a wall like this?
- 我砍的 到底是什么東西？ - 饕餮
- What the hell did we kill out there? - Tao Tei.
你殺了一只饕餮偵查兵
You killed a Tao Tei scout.
就憑你一個人
You killed it alone.
和我們預想的一樣 大戰將至
You are correct. We are under siege.
只是他們的攻擊 提前了九天
But we did not expect the attack for another nine days.
攻擊？
Attack?
- 饕餮？ - 饕餮是什么東西？
- Tao Tei? - What the hell is a Tao Tei?
我還有問題 要問你們
Many things about your story have importance.
所以 讓你們先活著
You are not to die today.
快！
Hurry!
啟稟軍師 鑰匙找不著了
I'm sorry, sir. I can not find the key.
算了！
Forget it!
帶他們上城 交熊軍 臨時看押！
Bring them to the wall. Keep an eye on them!
殿帥
General.
終于來了
It's finally happening.
是啊
Yes.
這一仗 等了六十年
60 years preparing for this moment.
站住！站住！
Stop! Stop!
進去 進去！
Go. Go!
進籠！
Inside!
站住！
Stand still!
坐下！坐下！
Get down! Get down!
黑色的 應該是步兵
The black are the foot soldiers.
- 紅的呢？ - 紅的是弓弩手
- And the red? - Those are the archers.
- 這藍色的是？ - 都是女人
- And the blue? - They're all women.
女人來搞什么？
What the hell do they do?
裝備精良啊
Look at this army.
- 你見過這樣的軍隊嗎？ - 真厲害
- Have you ever seen anything like this? - Incredible.
接槍！
Catch it!
你說城墻這么高
They look nervous.
他們到底緊張什么啊？
It's a big wall to be so nervous.
怎么聽著不對勁啊？
Do you hear it?
- 遠攻！ - 是！戰鼓隊傳令 遠攻！
- Long distance weapons! - Yes! Drums signal long distance weapons!
扶好！
Grab it!
點火！
Light it!
- 對準腋下之目！ - 對準腋下之目！
Aim for the eyes! Aim for the eyes!
飛索攻擊！
Crane Corps attack!
威廉 你看那里
William, over there.
他怎么沒被綁著？
Why isn't he tied up?
我們有機會了
There's our escape.
殿帥 那應該是獸王 牠在指揮
General. There's the queen. She commands them.
攻擊獸王！
Attack the queen!
- 近戰！ - 是！近戰！
- Close combat! - Yes! Close combat!
戰鼓隊傳令 近戰！
Drums signal close combat.
我們得離開！ 要不然 我們就死定了！
We need to move! We need to move or we die!
上 上！
Go, go!
上去打牠！
Go and fight!
快幫我解開！
Cut me loose!
- 打還是逃？ - 往哪里逃啊？
- Fight or run? - Run where?
射牠們的眼睛！
Aim for the eyes!
威廉！
William!
畜生！來啊！
Hey! Bitch!
- 威廉 - 引狼入室
- William. - I need a shot.
什么神 造出了這些怪物？
What god made those things?
反正不是我們的神
None that we know.
- 他們還會處死我們嗎？ - 哪倒省事了
- Think they'll hang us now? - I could use the rest.
- 聽說 今天打得不錯 - 我們殿帥 在夸獎你們
- You fought well today. - You've earned General Shao's praise.
- 牠們會回來嗎？ - 會的
- Will they come back? - Yes.
我們得隨時準備好
All we can do is prepare.
帶他們回營房
Take them to the barracks.
- 給他們準備一個房間 - 是！
- They need rest. - Yes!
感謝救命之恩
Thank you for saving my life.
林將軍
Commander Lin.
你從小 在禁軍中長大
You grew up in the Nameless Order.
我也教會了妳很多東西
I've taught you many things,
妳也在不斷的學習
and you have been learning,
但是牠們也在學習
but they have been learning also.
王軍師說過 牠們在變化
Strategist Wang warned they are evolving.
我們沒有認真聽
No one listened.
我們今天 面對的對手
The enemies we're facing today
已經不是六十年前的敵人了
are more intelligent than 60 years ago.
盯緊那兩個外邦
Watch the foreigners closely.
姑且好生款待
They can never leave.
- 一旦查明實情 立即處死 - 遵命！
- We must protect the secrets of the Wall. - Yes sir!
你是誰啊？
Who are you?
Easy.
等一下
我叫巴拉德
I'm Ballard.
我叫威廉
William.
他是托瓦爾
This is Tovar.
你們來干嘛？
What are you doing here?
- 當然是為了黑火藥了 - 果然不出我所料
- We came looking for black powder. - I bet you did.
25年前 我隨一隊雇傭兵來到這里
I came with merceneries for the same thing,
25 years ago.
也是為了這個？
And did you find it?
- 你找到了嗎？ - 找到了和活著帶出去 可是兩回事
Finding it and leaving with it alive are two different things.
不過 你們參加了戰斗 就等于是先下了步好棋
You saved the west turret. That was extremely diplomatic.
殺死怪獸 不是下棋
We weren't being diplomatic.
是為了保命
We were trying to stay alive.
- 你們身上的味道 像牲口 - 多謝
- You smell like animals. - Thank you.
洗干凈 會給你們飯吃
Clean up and they'll feed you.
他知道 黑火藥在哪里
He knows where the powder is.
那他怎么還在這里？
Then why is he still here?
他需要我們當幫手？
He needs help getting out?
可能
Right.
那就將計就計
We play our part,
拿了火藥 就回家
take the powder and go home.
- 你好像漏了一件大事？ - 什么大事？
- I didn't sign up for this. - Which part?
怪獸啊 白天那事 還不夠大啊
Well... All of it. But mostly the monsters.
的確是不小
There's a lot of them.
我們真的很臭
We really do smell.
歡迎貴客光臨
General Shao welcomes you as honored guests
我們邵殿帥
of the Nameless Order,
感謝你們參加戰斗 并贊賞你們勇氣可嘉
and thanks you for your skill and courage.
我們榮幸的榮幸
We are honored to be honored.
話都不會說了？
Is that the best you've got?
殿帥
General.
我們見過他的兵器
I couldn't help wondering,
想不通 像他這樣一位神箭手
why would such an accomplished archer
為何 會用這樣一張破弓？
used such a primitive bow.
陳將軍認為 你的弓 跟你身手不相配
Commander Chen thinks your bow is not worthy of your skill.
告訴他 這張弓 無與倫比
Tell him there's no better weapon here.
他說 這張弓 全城 獨一無二
He claims his weapon is second to none.
讓他給我們展示一下 讓將士們開開眼！
Let him show us. Give him some space!
- 大家想領教一下 - 在這里？
- They wish to see you shoot. - In here?
眾目睽睽 要是為難 就算了
Unless he's afraid. It's a large audience.
- 什么意思？ - 他說 當著這么多人
- What was that? - He thinks you have fear.
你怕出丑
Too many people.
- 你拿一只碗來 - 真練啊？
- Get one of the cups. - Now?
- 去拿一只碗來 - 我都快餓死了
- Get one of the cups. - I want to eat.
照老樣子？上次 你可演砸了
You remember how to do this? Last Time didn't go so good.
- 那是喝醉了 - 多醉？
- We were drunk. - How high?
十碼 向右 六掌
10 yards. Six hands to the right.
- 行不行啊 - 沒事 就這么來
- Turn around. - No. I'll do it this way.
- 聽我口令 - 我說 伙計…
- On my count. - Amigo...
一
One.
二
Two.
三
Three.
扔
Pull.
臭美夠了吧 我可得開始吃了
Good luck with that. I want food.
- 這里還有外國人？ - 你說巴拉德？
- Who taught you English? - Sir Ballard.
他來了很久了
English and Latin.
聽說 都已經25年了
Heard he's been here for twenty five years.
你們一直扣留他
You won't let him leave.
他必須留下
He must stay here.
那我們呢？
What about us?
輕松一點吃 一頓都少不了你的
Pace yourself. The meals are regular here.
我可沒想 像你待那么久
I hope not to stay that long.
這么想就對了
I like your thinking,
我勸你 還是別讓人看出來 你想干嘛
but I suggest you keep your plans private.
你們不是唯一 為了黑火藥而來的西方人
You aren't the first Westerners to come here looking for black powder.
今晚來我的房間 商量一下
We'll discuss it tonight. Bring your partner.
- 你在這里多久了？ - 一直都在
- How long have you been here? - Always.
我不到五歲的時候 就來這里了
I was not five years old when I came here.
我從小 就沒有家
I have no other family.
那我們是同類人
We're the same.
我也是被軍隊收養的 在我記事之前
I was given to an army before I can remember.
- 當了士兵？ - 不是 一名打掃
- As a soldier? - Worse. As a gleaner.
就是一群孩子  在戰斗結束之后 負責打掃戰場
Packs of children, we'd clean the battlefields.
后來成了侍衛
After, when the fighting's over, I became a page.
- 一名長茅兵 - 為了你的國家？
- a pikeman's boy. - For Your country?
不 為了填飽肚子
No. I fought for food.
為了生存
You fight to eat.
也是為了錢而戰
You live long enough, you fight for money.
你可以為任何國家賣命？
How many flag do you fight for?
我不確定
I don't know.
我幫哈羅德 打丹麥人
I fought for Harold against the Danes.
救了公爵的命 他死之前 我一直替他打戰
I saved a Duke's life. I fought for him until he died.
我幫西班牙人 打法蘭克人
Fought for Spain against the Franks.
又幫法蘭克人 打布倫人
Fought for Franks against Boulogne.
還為教皇打過仗
I fought for the Pope.
很多國家
Many flags.
我們并不是同類人
We are not the same.
來城墻上找我 讓你見識一下
Meet me on the Wall. I have something to show you.
這個女人 你得防著一點
He should be careful with her.
她可不是省油的燈
She's very powerful here.
正好 我們也不省油
Then it is a fair contest.
上來
Come.
敢不敢試試？
You wish to try?
男人那么重 拉得上來嗎？
Men are too heavy. Do you think we can pull him up?
她說 男人可以做很好的示范
She says men have so much to teach us.
我覺得 她說的 不是這個意思
I don't think that's what she said.
我看出來了？
You know what I think?
你是怕出丑了
I think you're afraid.
射箭前 妳也這么說
You said that this morning.
我這不是…
And yet,
來了嗎？
here I am.
好啊
Yes.
那來吧
Here you are.
你是跳？還是不跳？
Will you jump? Or not?
- 他們靠得住嗎？ - 這你不用操心
- These men know what they're doing? - Wrong question.
你該操心的是  你身上的繩子 綁好了沒有
Whether or not the cable is attached, that is the question.
- 關鍵是？ - 信任
- And the answer? - Xin ren.
信任？
Xin ren?
信任 彼此之間 相信
Xin ren means trust. To have faith.
我們這支軍隊  不為錢和食物而戰
Here, in this army, we fight for more than food or money.
我們的犧牲 更有意義
We give our lives to something more.
我們以信任為旗幟 彼此支持 相互信任
Xin ren is our flag. Trust in each other.
不論何時 不論何地
In all ways, at all times.
妳說的有道理 但我還是不跳
Well, that's all well and good, but I'm not jumping.
我能活到今天 就因為 只信自己
I'm alive today because I trust no one.
其實 你信任別人 就是相信自己
A man must learn to trust, before he can be trusted.
妳說的對
Then you were right.
我們不是同類人
We're not the same.
快！下次襲擊 隨時開始！
Stay vigilant! The next attack is coming!
我的天！
My god!
讓你們先開開眼
A taste, a glimpse,
這點黑火藥
a few pilfered grains
還是我從王軍師哪里 偷偷弄來的 很珍貴
from Strategist Wang's supply of black powder.
王軍師這個人 對黑火藥 可是很有研究
He's mastered the transmutation of these elements.
據說有種火藥武器
People speak of a weapon.
這里的武器 五花八門
There are many weapons here.
我怎么沒見到啊？
Why have we not seen them?
你沒見過的東西多著呢
There are many things you have not seen.
你應該禱告
And many things you should pray
打仗的時候 千萬別碰到牠 否則 你就玩完了
will not be needed before the siege is through.
饕餮還會回來的
The Tao Tei will return.
當戰鼓響起的時候
When the drums call to battle,
全體將士 上城墻 各就各位
the guards leave their post and take their positions on the Wall.
那就是我們逃跑的機會
That is our moment.
只要他們一打起來… 我們就開溜
We want to be riding away as the battle rages.
那火藥倉庫的門呢？
And the armory doors?
- 你有鑰匙？ - 黑火藥 我這里還有
- You have keys? - I have black powder,
夠炸開好幾道門的
enough for several doors.
我們互相協作 各取所需 離開這里
He brings us in. We get us out.
王軍師有請諸位
Strategist Wang request your presence.
你搏斗時  這塊石頭 到底在哪里？
As you fought, where was this stone?
在我包里
In my bag.
真是無形的力量
Its unseen force is powerfull.
看來 得好好研究一下這塊石頭
I believe this strange stone could help us.
玄機何在
We try everything.
- 饕餮現在在哪里？ - 鉤吾山 準備攻擊
- Where are the Tao Tei now? - The mountains, regrouping.
牠們從哪里來的？
Where do they come from?
在2000多年前
About 20 centuries ago,
有一位皇帝 貪婪無度 令民不聊生
There was an emperor whose greed brought deep suffering to all of China.
激怒上蒼 天降隕石 擊中鉤吾山
The heaven sent a meteor that struck Gouwu Mountain
綠光中 釋放出饕餮
turning it green and releasing Tao Tei.
從此 中國北方的土地上  六十年 一個輪回
From that day on, the Tao Tei rise every sixty years,
幾經饕餮的肆虐
to scourge the north of China.
以此告誡世人 貪婪的后果
They come to remind us of what happens when greed is unchecked.
饕餮兵獸 見人就吃 無論生死
They eat anything, alive or dead,
只是為了去填飽獸王的肚皮
and take food to their queen. She depends on her soldiers to feed her.
饕餮獸王不捕食 全靠兵獸喂養牠 獸王吃飽了 就會大量的繁殖
Only with the food they provide is she able to multiply.
離長城八百里以外的汴梁
The capital and its 2 million people,
那里有兩百萬的人口
is only 800 li away.
如果這兩百萬的人口 變成他們充足的食物
If the Tao Tei ever had that much nourisment
那么天下 將永無寧日
no corner of the world would be safe.
- 為什么不去殺了牠們？ - 當然試過 他們去了
- You cann't hunt them? - Men try. They disappear.
一個也沒回來
We never find their bones.
紹殿帥 緊急巡查西箭樓！
Troops unaccounted for at the West Tower!
牠們為何丟下尸體？
Why did they leave the bodies?
下馬！
Dismount!
建陣！
Formation!
前進！
Advance!
停一下
Stop.
林將軍
Commander Lin.
殿帥…
General...
牠們又進步了
They led us into a trap.
懂得偷襲我們的要害了
We underestimated their intelligence.
禁軍…
The Nameless Order...
- 就交給妳了 - 殿帥…
- is yours to command. - General...
眾將軍 聽令…
Commanders, this is my final order...
從今天起
from this day forward,
林將軍 就是你們的殿帥
Commander Lin will lead you.
禁軍全體將士 愿接受林將軍的率領
The soldiers of the Nameless Order will stand firm.
保家衛國！誓滅饕餮！
The wall must not fall! We will defeat the Tao Tei!
- 請殿帥放心！ - 請殿帥放心！
- Rest in peace. - Rest in peace!
∮ 秦時明月 漢時關
∮ 萬里長征 人未還
∮ 但使龍城 飛將在
∮ 不叫胡馬 渡陰山
樞密院特使 沈大人
This is envoy Shen from the palace.
他特地從汴梁帶來史料 協助我們對付饕餮
He has brought important records to help with the coming battle.
- 據九百多年前史料記載 - 九百年前的史料上寫道
- This is a 900 years old batte report. - A 900 years old battle report.
當年在寒沙門  有三只饕餮 爬上了城樓
At the Hans Gate, three beasts mounted the wall.
越過城樓 沿途殺了很多人
They killed many men as they went forward.
但是 也許是天上神的力量
Then, by the grace of the ancient gods,
饕餮 突然停了下來
the beasts stopped
靜止不動了  士兵上前 將其斬殺
and sat peacefully, as we slaughtered them.
當時現場有一塊磁石 跟這一塊一樣
There was a magnet on site just like this one.
當年在寒沙門  也有一塊 像這樣的磁石
At the Hans Gate, was a magnet just like this one.
他說 是因為你身上的這塊磁石
I believe that magnet was the reason the two of you Westerners
你才能輕而易舉地 把那只饕餮殺死了
killed the Tao Tei so easily.
他覺得是磁石 讓饕餮的耳朵聾了
I believe the magnet makes the Tao Tei deaf.
饕餮聽不到獸王的指令  就靜止了
Without instruction, they fall still.
- 此事如何驗證？ - 確實難以驗證
- How to prove that? - How can we be sure?
試試就行？
Why not try it?
只要抓一只饕餮 測試一下
Capture a Tao Tei. See if it works.
- 他說他要嘗試一下 就得抓一只 - 怎么抓？
- He wants to try. He wants to catch one. - How?
根本沒有那么結實的網
No net is strong enough.
直接抓 就像捕鯨 你知道我在說什么
Hunt them. Like a whale. You know what that is.
是一種水中的巨獸 可比饕餮大百十倍
A water beast. A hundred times the size of a Tao Tei.
用帶勾的叉 勾住牠 鉤住骨頭
A spear that grabs. Hook the bone.
然后 把牠拉上來
Pulled them up.
用有鉤的魚叉  直接就可以把牠抓住
Use a spear, hook them. So we can catch them.
我在西班牙見過
I've seen it done in Spain.
他說 他在西班牙見過
He claims to have seen it done in Spain.
你跟著瞎攪合什么啊？
What the hell are you doing?
只要他們一打起來 我們就得逃
We need to be free when the attack comes.
這可是唯一的機會？
How many chances do you think we will get?
裝受傷 玩失蹤 做個膽小鬼 行嗎？
Be injured. Be missing. Be a coward.
別再瞎摻和了
Get out of this.
我們夠意思了
We did enough.
你們要調稠一點 才能麻醉牠
The mixture must be strong to put the creature to sleep.
- 把麻藥涂勻了 - 是！
- Spread it on evenly. - Yes, Commander!
楞什么？
Snap out of it!
給我滾到伙房去 不要再上來！
Useless idiot! report to the kitchen where you belong!
- 遵命 - 滾！
- Yes, Commander. - Go!
- 他會來的 - 什么時候？等打完仗？
- He'll be here. - When? When it was over?
- 那我們邊干邊等 - 邊干邊等？
- We will start and he will find us. - Start?
開弓沒有回頭箭 我把一切都準備好了
We're jumping off a cliff here. I have everything.
火藥 工具 地圖
Powder, tools, maps.
都藏在逃跑的沿途
It's all hidden and arranged along the route.
一旦動手 根本沒時間等他
Once we start, there's no going back.
- 敢死隊 上！ - 是！敢死隊上！
- Death Squad ready! - Yes! Death Squad go!
大刀準備！
Blades ready!
大刀起！
Blades forward!
- 攻擊！ - 上！
- Attack! - Go!
- 左！左！ - 右！右！
Left! Right!
- 我去找他 - 甭管他了
- I'll find him. - Forget him.
他現在 一心只想著討好那個女殿帥
He'd rather die trying to impress the new general
你說 等拿到火藥 有了錢 什么妞不能玩啊？
than grab the key to every counting room and brothel in the world.
- 不能再等了 現在就得行動 - 不能扔下他
Good God, man. The time is now. I can't go without him.
- 少一個人分錢 不是更好！ - 我們需要他的弓！
- More the spoils for us! - We need his bow!
魚叉箭！
Harpoons!
- 魚叉箭 放！ - 是！魚叉箭 放！
- Harpoons, Now! - Yes! Harpoons, fire!
齊放！
Fire!
去！
There!
- 讓開！ - 最后一根了！
- Move! - It's the last one!
- 再拉！ - 不 不 不 停！
- Pull! - No, no, no. Stop!
停一下！
Hold!
你們拉得太緊！ 鏈子會斷的
There's too much tension! Chain will break.
- 先松一下 先松一下 - 慢點！慢點！
- That way. That way. - Let him run!
停！停！我們得等一下 等麻藥起作用了
Stop! Stop! We need longer for the sleeping potion to work.
拉 拉起來
That way. That way.
得想辦法 擋開其他饕餮
We need to isolate it. Sparate it from the others.
- 火球保護！ - 是！火球保護！
- Ring of Fire! - Yes! Ring of Fire!
- 鐵鏈要斷了！ - 不好啦！
- The chain won't hold much longer! - We're losing him!
- 威廉 等等 響箭！ - 是！響箭！
- William, wait. Screaming arrows! - Yes! Screaming arrows!
中了響箭的饕餮 一跑就會響
These arrows will scream as the Tao Tei run.
瞄準聲音射箭
Aim for the sound.
火球圈內 響箭覆蓋！
Aim inside the circle. Blanket the whole area.
放！
Fire!
收！
Pull!
救你一命 是因為 我想親手宰了你
I'm only saving you so I can kill you myself.
撿把斧頭 盲打
Grab the axe, we're fighting blind.
- 可能現在做不是… - 你少廢話！
- Not yet! - I know what to do!
- 火焰擋不住牠們了 - 那就永別吧 兄弟
- The fire is not holding them back here. - Die well, brother.
- 你在干嘛？ - 給她發信號！
- What the hell are you doing? - She's listening.
- 火藥箭 霹靂彈準備！ - 是 火藥箭 霹靂彈準備！
- Prepare black powder weapon! - Prepare black powder weapon!
佩戴火繩！
Prepare to light the fuses!
是！佩戴火繩！
Yes! Prepare to light the fuses!
- 成功了？ - 是的
- Did it work? - Yes.
抓了只活的
The beast was captured.
- 那我朋友呢？ - 放心 他沒事
- My friend... - He was unharmed.
你為什么要跳下去？
Why did you go over the Wall?
信任 我說的 對嗎？
Xin ren. Did I say that right?
謝謝你
Thank you.
我們的黑火藥
Black powder.
是一種可怕的武器
It is a terrible weapon.
我真希望你 不曾見過這一切
It would be better if you had never see it.
我對外面的世界 了解的并不是很多
I know very little of the outside world.
在我看來  人類與饕餮的貪婪 并無區別
But it seems to me, the greed of men is not that different than the Tao Tei.
我說的 對嗎？
Is that true?
全都是弱肉強食
The strong take what they want.
忘掉你所看到的一切
Forget what you have seen.
好！即刻押送汴梁
Excellent! Send it to the capital immediately.
不可！需就地研究
No! We need to study it here.
饕餮若能活捉 皇上必須先睹
If a Tao Tei is captured alive, it must be sent to the emperor.
下官特地為此事而來 這可是皇上的旨意
This is an Imperial Order.
你會成為一個勇敢的士兵
You're much braver than they think.
沒受傷吧？
You're wounded?
剛才我在找你
I was looking for you.
是想跟你說 謝謝你
To say thank you.
感覺特別好吧？ 想不想唱兩句啊？
You feel good, huh? Maybe you sing a little song, eh?
要不 一起唱
I will join you.
歌頌一個偉大的英雄 拯救了中國人
We can sing together how you saved the gratefull Chinos.
干嘛這么說  一切你都看到了？
You saw what happened out there, and that's what you say?
我看到了黑火藥
I see black powder.
- 也看到 你忘了朋友 - 放心吧 黑火藥又不會跑
- I see a man forget his friends. - The black powder's not going anywhere.
我看 不會跑的是你
What goes nowhere is you.
你永遠都得不到你想要的
You'll never get what you want from this.
你以為 他們能把你當大英雄啊？
You think they see you as some kind of hero?
想當救世主？你蒙得了他們
A man of virtue? Maybe you can fool them,
但是你蒙不了我
but I know what you are.
你心里 應該也很清楚
You know what you are.
你就是個賊 是個混混
A thief, a liar,
是個殺手
and a killer.
想放下屠刀 立地成佛？
You can never undo things you've done.
狗改不了吃屎
and you will never be anything.
這才像是我哥們
Good to see you again, amigo.
發現饕餮！發現饕餮！發現饕餮！
Tao Tei movement!
全體上城！全體上城！
All troops to the Wall!
- 人呢？ - 不管他了
- Nothing? - No.
- 你確定 他不會出賣我們？ - 不會的
- How do you know he won't betray us? - I don't.
他們會殺了他 不管怎么樣都會
They'll kill him. They'll kill him no matter what.
他們殺他的時候
The time they spend killing him,
我們已經帶著東西跑遠了
is time they are not chasing us.
小心一點 這可有黑火藥
Careful with that. There's powder here.
托瓦爾
Tovar.
殿帥 打通了！ 饕餮已突破長城！
General, it goes all the way through. Tao Tei have breached the wall.
牠們居然如此狡猾
They're smarter than we thought.
- 傳令所有將軍 立即來此！ - 遵命！
- Summon my commanders immediately! - Yes, General!
去看看 是不是滅了
Have a look. See if it's gone out.
- 安全嗎？ - 安全啊
- Is it safe? - Of course it is.
醒醒 開工了
Shake it off, man. To work.
安全？差點要了我的命
I thought you said it was safe?
結果 還是不錯的
We're in, didn't we?
- 你來了 - 終于醒悟了啊？
- You're here. - We've come to our senses, eh?
他的計劃很周密 逃出去 并不難
Ballard has planned well. Getting out is easy.
從這里往西 走二十英里后出長城
There's a gate. 20 miles west. We dodge the hill tribes.
- 只要我們避開契丹人 - 那就大功告成了
- We can make it. - They need us here.
這里需要我們
They need more than us.
需要的人多了
- These people are doomed. - Don't be a fool.
- 留下來 就是個死 - 別傻了
I've been a fool.
我過去才傻 現在不會了
I'm done with it.
哥們 求你了
Brother, please.
過去的戰斗 毫無意義
We've been fighting for nothing.
只是貪婪
For greed.
聽我說 哥們  我們歷盡千辛萬苦 百般磨難
Amigo, after all the blood, the cold, and pain,
好不容易有了黑火藥  目的達到了
with this black powder in our saddle bags, we win.
跟我們一起走吧
You come with me.
我不能這么做
I can't do that now.
- 留下來 跟我一起戰斗 - 威廉…
- Stay and fight. - William...
- 他死了嗎？ - 沒那么容易死
- Think he's dead? - It'd take a lot more than that.
沒想到 牠們前兩次 都是佯攻  我們都上當了
All of the attacks have been a diversion, while they dug this tunnel.
過了長城
They have breached the wall.
汴梁有牠們無窮無盡的食物  后果不堪設想
Once they reach the capital, nothing in the world can stop them.
我的騎兵 就算是快馬加鞭  也得兩天 才能到汴梁
At a full gallop, it's two days to the capital.
- 牠們肯定比我們快 - 現在風很強
- There's no way we can catch them. - The wind is strong now.
明天一整天吹北風 我們必須啟用新發明
It blows from the north all day tomorrow. We have to use the balloons.
- 到汴梁要多久？ - 順風約三個時辰
- If it works, how long to Bianliang? - Six hours if the wind hold.
如果能活著的話
If we make it alive.
殿帥 這些東西 從沒試過
General, none of the tests have worked.
準備出發！
Get ready!
走！
Come on!
首都  汴梁
THE CAPITAL BIANLIANG
- 怎么抓的？ - 啟稟皇上！
- How did you capture it? - Your Excellency!
皇上  是那塊磁石 能制住這畜生
Your Excellency, It's the magnet. It keeps the beast under control.
自饕餮成禍以來 此發現 最為重大
This is the most important discovery in the history of the Tao Tei.
- 樞密院將立即展開研究 - 把他拉下來！
- We will investigate immediately. - Bring him here!
- 我試著… - 你還敢在此狡辯？
- I tried to stop... - You dare to speak to me?
- 這事不是我干的 - 是啊 你說 你是個商人
- I didn't do this. - And you came here to trade.
你并不是為了黑火藥而來
And you knew nothing of black powder.
你一定覺得 我是個傻子 是吧
What a fool you must think I am.
如果我們是一伙的  我還會在這里嗎？我是要阻止他們
If I was with them, why would I be here? I tried to stop them.
騙子！
Liar!
你是個騙子
You lie.
- 你心里知道 不是這樣的 - 如果我不是殿帥
- Some part of you knows that's not true. - If I were not the General,
我會親手殺了你
I would kill you myself.
殿帥！
General!
- 啟稟殿帥 - 大聲點！
- General. - Speak up.
事發時 小人正在翰淵閣 小人親眼看見 他阻攔那兩個人
I was there when it happened. I saw him try to stop them.
你確定嗎？
Are you sure?
你敢說半句假話 我先鍘了你！
If you're lying, I'll have your head!
小人以無影禁軍的名譽起誓 所說 絕無半句虛言！
I swear on my vow to the Nameless Order!
嚴加看管
Lock him up.
派騎兵隊 把那兩個盜賊抓回來！
Send the cavalry. Go after the two that got away.
遵命！
Yes, General.
往左 還是往右？
Which way, left or right?
得去高處看一下才知道
Go up and take a look from the high ground.
不！
不！混蛋！
No! Bastard!
- 把牢方向！ - 是 把牢方向！
- Keep it steady! - Yes, General!
- 小心火藥！ - 是 小心火藥！
- Watch the powder! - Yes, General!
出什么事了？
What happened?
- 怎么了 軍師？ - 我們失敗了
What happened? We have failed.
饕餮已經越過長城
The Tao Tei are in the kingdom.
你自由了 想要什么 就拿上走吧
You are free to leave. Take what you wish and go.
- 這是殿帥最后的命令 - 她在哪里？
- This was the General's final order. - Where is she?
她去干什么？戰斗？
To do what? To fight?
- 能打勝嗎？ - 只有一種可能
- Is there a chance? - There's only one.
殺死獸王 獸王不死 我們都會死
Kill the Queen. Kill the Queen, or we all die.
回家吧 把你所看到的一切
Leave. Tell the world what you have seen,
告訴世人 大難將至
and tell them what is coming.
我的弓在哪里？
I'll need my bow.
我要和你們一起 參加戰斗
If I'm to join you, I'll need my bow.
啟稟軍師！帶上我
Strategist Wang! Please take me with you.
他想和我們一起去
He wishes to join us.
距離不同
The distance is the key.
這畜生的反應也不同
The magnet is only effective when close to the beast.
所以 磁石的遠近
Therefore, the effect weakens as it gets further away.
才是研究的重點
You see I have it under complete control.
記下了 九尺
Write down nine feet.
- 往后飛 后殿！ - 是！后殿！
- Steer to the rear of the palace. - Yes! To the rear of the palace!
上面！
Above you!
- 霹靂彈！ - 是 霹靂彈！
- Light a grenade! - Yes, sir!
快接著！
Behind you!
我讓你回家的
I set you free.
我還是來了
And here I am.
獸王在那里！
There's the queen!
牠們在進食 不會進攻
They will not attack while the queen is feeding.
這是我們的機會！抓住！
We have a chance! Hold on!
來者何人？
State your purpose!
無影禁軍 殿帥 林梅 參見皇上！
General Lin Mae from Nameless Order. At your service!
你們怎么回事？
What took you so long?
饕餮都沖到朕的門口了！
The Tao Tei overrun the city!
朕的幾千御林軍 還有無數的黎民百姓
Thousands of soldiers and innocent are dead.
一眨眼 全都沒了！
You're too late!
被捕獲的那個饕餮 現在在哪？
Where is the captured Tao Tei?
- 關地牢了！ - 要利用牠殺死獸王
- In the dungeon! - We need it to kill the queen.
獸王死了 信號就斷了
Once she is dead, The Tao Tei can not function.
成千上萬的饕餮 就會僵住無用
Without her signal, their whole army will freeze.
這里有一條地下通道
There is an underground canal here.
沒有饕餮嗎？
Has it been breached?
現在 應該都在地上
The Tao Tei should all be above ground.
這是我們抓的那只？
And the one we captured?
帶上牠
We load it up.
喂飽了以后 牠會回去找獸王
We feed him. And it will return to its queen.
好主意
Good.
你會留下一個傷疤 但是很酷
You'll have one hell of a scar,
- but you'll live.
- He says you will live.
他說 你會活著
回頭再救他
We'll come back for him.
牠們攻進來了！
They've broken through!
威廉 別放箭
Patience, William.
牠吃飽了之后 會去找獸王？
And it will go to the Queen when it's done?
應該會
It should.
我確定
It will.
放牠進去
Let it in.
我能從上面 把箭射進去
I can get a shot from above.
上去！我擋住牠們
Go! I'll hold them back.
快 牠接近獸王了
Wait. Not yet.
中
Hit.
再上 牠們護不住頭頂
Go higher. I'll get a better shot.
殿帥！全靠你們了！
General! It's up to you now!
只剩一件火藥武器了 把火藥槍給我
We have one black powder weapon left. Give me the spear.
我苦練一生 只為此戰
I've trained for this my whole life.
信任
Trust.
我們相互信任
I'll get you the shot.
抓緊我！
I've got you.
怎么樣 有沒有想我啊？
So, how's life without me?
有一點無聊
A little slow.
- 聽說 你是大英雄了 - 那是必須的
- You're a hero after all. - Oh, it looks that way.
瞧你得意的樣子
You seem pleased with yourself..
拯救世界的大英雄 有什么獎勵？
And what are they giving you for all your troubles?
一袋金子？
A bag of gold?
還是在長城上 為你嘉喜慶典？
A victory parade along the top of the Wall?
黑火藥 我隨便拿
All the black powder I can carry.
而且派騎兵 保護我回家
And a cavalry escort to get me home safely.
- 那恭喜你了 - 謝謝
- Well, congratulations. - Thank you.
所以 你就？
So what is this?
- 跟我這顯擺？ - 那當然啦？
- You're here to rub my nose in it? - Well, would you blame me?
你上次 把我一個人扔下來等死
The last time I saw you, you left me for dead.
再上次 我還救你一條命呢
And the time before, I saved your life.
倒也是
True.
其實 皇上給我兩個選擇
You know, the Emperor gave me a choice.
帶走黑火藥…或著帶走你
I could take the black powder or I could take you.
那你可千萬別選我
Please tell me you chose the powder.
你讓我很失望啊
I don't even know you anymore.
馬已經備好了 日落前 我們就可以出發
The horses are saddled and waiting. Best we ride before nightfall.
我回避
I'll be inside.
走時 可記得叫我啊
Don't leave without me.
我是來道別的
I came to say goodbye.
聽說妳 榮升驃騎大將軍了
I understand congratulations are in order.
我真的 很為妳感到高興
General of the northwest territory.
應該祝賀妳
Quite an honor.
看來 你已經選擇好了
Seems you've made your choice.
他啊？說實話  我真的想用這小子換黑火藥
Oh, him? Believe me, I'm already think about trading him back for the powder.
我可聽著呢
I heard that.
也許 我們都說得不對
Perhaps we were both wrong.
其實 我們就是一類人
We are more similar than I thought.
謝謝大將軍
Thank you General.
- 你不想留下來陪她？ - 當然想啊
- Are you sure you don't want to go back? - Of course I do.
但我怕你一個人 回不了家
I just don't trust you to make it out of here alone.